<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scope of Public Defender’s authority on Ombudsman - Preview</title>
    <link>https://ochrance-preview.netlify.app/en/pusobnost/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scope of Public Defender’s authority on Ombudsman - Preview</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>cs</language><atom:link href="https://ochrance-preview.netlify.app/en/pusobnost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Equal treatment and discrimination</title>
      <link>https://ochrance-preview.netlify.app/en/pusobnost/rovne-zachazeni-a-diskriminace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ochrance-preview.netlify.app/en/pusobnost/rovne-zachazeni-a-diskriminace/</guid>
      <description>While the “traditional” competence of the Ombudsman only applies to authorities and institutions performing State administration, in the area of discrimination, the Ombudsman may also address complaints against discriminatory conduct of municipalities (e.g. in renting of municipal flats), employers (in recruitment procedure, remuneration, termination of employment, etc.), vendors (in offering products and services), schools and others.
In general, discrimination means different treatment in comparable situations without a reasonable justification. The feeling of being discriminated against is not sufficient in itself – legally speaking, discrimination only means conduct described and prohibited by law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family, healthcare and labour</title>
      <link>https://ochrance-preview.netlify.app/en/pusobnost/rodina-zdravotnictvi-a-prace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ochrance-preview.netlify.app/en/pusobnost/rodina-zdravotnictvi-a-prace/</guid>
      <description>Family In most cases, people seek help with problems in the area of family life, especially when they are dissatisfied with the procedure taken by a body for social and legal protection of children (BSLPC). This includes situations where a parent prevents the other parent from contacting their child, where there is a risk of removal of a child from the family or where the guardian ad litem does not protect the child’s interest in court proceedings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judiciary, migration, finance</title>
      <link>https://ochrance-preview.netlify.app/en/pusobnost/justice-migrace-finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ochrance-preview.netlify.app/en/pusobnost/justice-migrace-finance/</guid>
      <description>State administration of courts As regards the activities of courts, people most often complain about delays in court proceedings or inappropriate conduct of judicial persons and infringement of dignity in proceedings. According to the Courts and Judges Act, these complaints are to be dealt with by the president of the court and the Ombudsman may examine how the complaint was resolved. We also deal with activities of the Ministry of Justice, administration of the Public Prosecutor’s Office and administrative affairs concerning experts/interpreters and other legal professions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring of rights of people with disabilities </title>
      <link>https://ochrance-preview.netlify.app/en/pusobnost/ochrana-prav-osob-se-zdravotnim-postizenim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ochrance-preview.netlify.app/en/pusobnost/ochrana-prav-osob-se-zdravotnim-postizenim/</guid>
      <description>To this end, we have conducted inquiries and surveys and drawn up recommendations to improve the situation of people with disabilities. In doing so, we co-operate directly with people with disabilities and non-profit organisations. We also deal with the procedure of municipalities acting in the capacity of public guardians.
Our activities are based on practical findings. The Ombudsman has an advisory body composed of people with disabilities and disability advocates. The role of the advisory body is to look out for systemic problems, assist in setting priorities and making recommendations, and identify issues that need to be addressed in the area of the rights of people with disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public order</title>
      <link>https://ochrance-preview.netlify.app/en/pusobnost/verejny-poradek/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ochrance-preview.netlify.app/en/pusobnost/verejny-poradek/</guid>
      <description>We also focus on property law, i.e., especially the activities of land registry offices and land-use authorities. We deal with problems in civil service and employment with the State (service relationships), provision of information, personal data protection and conduct of the Police (unless it acts in the capacity of a prosecuting body).
Each year, we deal with over 2,000 complaints.
 A case of an inaccessible road to a cabin</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rules of construction procedure</title>
      <link>https://ochrance-preview.netlify.app/en/pusobnost/stavebni-rad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ochrance-preview.netlify.app/en/pusobnost/stavebni-rad/</guid>
      <description>Construction People most often seek help in connection with a structure’s placement and/or approval. Another major area includes proceedings on removal of a structure and the related proceedings on additional approval of a structure. We also deal with complaints concerning use of a structure for other purposes than those covered by the occupancy permit. People also complain about the construction authorities’ inactivity in addressing buildings in a state of disrepair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social security</title>
      <link>https://ochrance-preview.netlify.app/en/pusobnost/socialni-zabezpeceni/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ochrance-preview.netlify.app/en/pusobnost/socialni-zabezpeceni/</guid>
      <description>Pensions Every year, we deal with approximately 500 complaints related to pensions. Disability pension is the most common subject of complaints, followed by retirement pension. We also deal with survivors’ pensions (widow’s/widower’s/orphan’s pension) and miner’s pensions. People usually disagree with the amount of pension granted, they complain that not all periods of insurance have been taken into account in the calculation or that an incorrect disability onset date was used, among other reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supervision over restrictions of personal freedom </title>
      <link>https://ochrance-preview.netlify.app/en/pusobnost/dohled-nad-omezovanim-osobni-svobody/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ochrance-preview.netlify.app/en/pusobnost/dohled-nad-omezovanim-osobni-svobody/</guid>
      <description>These places include not only prisons and police cells, but also facilities for children, retirement homes, facilities for people with disabilities, treatment facilities for long-term patients, psychiatric hospitals, infant care centres, facilities for detention of foreigners, etc.
What is the national preventive mechanism?  Apart from that, we primarily deal with complaints raised by imprisoned persons, patients of psychiatric hospitals undergoing institutional forensic treatment and foreigners residing in facilities for foreigners.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
